Who from our generation didn't dance
to this wonderful classic piece
back in the 1960s –
at the "Samba 'Arpége' Club"?
Waldir had an orchestra.
They played at all the graduation parties.
And that chorus? Who sings it?
– The musicians themselves? – Yes.
And this friend of yours.
– Yes, I was there too. – Nice.
In fact, Waldir himself also sang the chorus.
Wonderful.
“Those who lack life, You see, dare not dance
Samba at the 'Arpége' Club Can't be sweeter.”
Let's listen.
“Samba at the 'Arpége' Club,” Luiz Bandeira and Waldir Calmon.
Our story takes place
in Brazil in 1977,
in very mischievous times...
Hey.
Fill it to the top?
Don’t worry, everything is fine.
– Fill it?   – Well...
Yes, fill it, but...
What happened there?
It happened last Sunday.
The poor devil came with a knife to steal cans of oil...
Rivanildas, the night worker, grabbed a twelve-gauge shotgun.
and shot him in the chest and face.
And he lay there.
The jerk got what he deserved.
Don't worry, you are the customer.
That's not related to you.
Good?
Well, okay.
Drive a little back.
– Closer to the pump.
– Alright.
– Has he been there since Sunday?
– Yes.
I will tell you the whole story.
He has been there since the carnival weekend,
Sunday night.
Rivanildas called the owners.
Me too.
No response.
Rivanildas fled,
so he wouldn't be caught at the crime scene.
He went to the carnival party.
And I stayed here with this mess.
Open the hood.
If I leave,
I will lose my job.
If I stay,
I will be left with decomposing flesh.
I have almost gotten used to this crap.
How much?
– Stop at 120, please.
– Okay.
You didn't call the police?
Oh, the police...
We called them, they said,
that they would come by on Ash Wednesday,
because they have too much work during the carnival.
So far, there’s no sign of them.
Today is Tuesday.
They started to stink yesterday.
Look at what the dogs are doing?
Hey, dogs!
Get out of here!
Go away!
Damn bastards, get out!
Get lost!
What the hell.
Thank you.
Goodbye.
Finally.
Thank you.
FEDERAL HIGHWAY POLICE
He has been there since Sunday.
You weren’t in a hurry.
We didn’t even know about this.
And I was drowning in this trouble at the time.
– Good morning, sir.
– Good morning.
Your driver's license and documents, please.
So you’re not here for the body?
Not at all,
my partner asked me to stop and check
the yellow "Beetle."
Please show me the fire extinguisher.
Could you step out of the car, sir?
Why?
I need to get inside the car.
You can trust me.
Is it really necessary?
Yes.
Please step out.
Wait here, okay?
The extinguisher is in order.
Yes...
in order.
No drugs in the car?
You don’t smoke weed?
No.
Weapons?
I’m not carrying a weapon.
Drive on, don’t stop.
Nobody wants to stop.
Isn’t that spare tire too worn out?
That’s a good spare tire.
Well, alright.
Listen, sir...
Could you...
donate to the police carnival fund?
Captain...
Not a captain, I’m a sergeant.
Sergeant.
I’ve been driving for three days.
I spent all the remaining money on gasoline.
But if you want...
You can take some of these. Cigarettes.
Can I keep them?
Of course.
Get lost! Get out of here!
Away!
Ugh!
Damn you, stupid fools.
SECRET AGENT
From Pernambuco – to the world.
Good afternoon to the listeners of “Jornal do Commercio”!
DRIVEN BY ME,
GUIDED BY GOD
It's Fat Tuesday.
So, are you enjoying the heartache of betrayal?
Is it hard for you?
Then lean back and enjoy Chicago,
"If You Leave Me Now."
WITCHCRAFT IS A POOR MAN'S TWIST
PART 1
BOY'S NIGHTMARE
OCEANOGRAPHY DEPARTMENT
Oh brother!
- I bless you, father.
- God bless you.
Officer Euclid.
Wait a minute.
I need to talk to my men, okay?
Go, step back.
Before going inside...
tell me what's going on.
Well, father...
I think it was that guy
from last week.
What?
What? Are you crazy?
Do you think I would call the father from the carnival
if it wasn't serious?
Who's in charge here?
The artist, from the Kordeiro precinct.
I can't stand that piece of crap.
Fernando isn't here?
He is enjoying the carnival.
- Are there journalists?
- No.
Just one scientist and a few students.
Right or left?
I couldn't see, I was too far away.
Suspicious.
Officer Euclid, you shouldn't have come.
I'm almost done.
I am Euclid Kavalkančis, police chief.
At your service.
The individual was found on Sunday,
we need to act quickly.
- Don't you have a refrigerator?
- It's broken.
When we were working, we found a part...
that is, a leg.
I started to pull it,
but I decided better not to.
We called the police.
Damn...
Where was that shark found,
or killed?
150 meters from the shore.
There, in Kandeja.
And the leg...
is it a man's?
Better not say anything for now.
That's the work of forensic experts.
- Are you going to cut it with a knife? No need.
- Don't worry, I'm experienced.
You will mess up the individual.
I will remove it myself.
Please wait there.
No knives.
Hand over the gloves.
Professor, just one question.
Did you take photos?
No, there's no photos.
Professor,
was the shark male or female?
Male.
Damn!
Crap!
Mission accomplished.
God, you're soaking wet!
Here.
- Dona Sebastijana?
- Yes, at your service.
- Marselas?
- Yes.
- How are you?
- Great.
- I need you to give me a ride.
- Of course, get in.
This is Klovis.
Get on the footrest, boy!
- Is everything okay?
- Yes.
- Are you comfortable?
Let's go.
Did the cops not catch you when they saw your beard?
Today they robbed me!
- How?
- They took my cigarettes.
Don't give them anything!
You can take my cigarettes.
I would never let them take mine.
How long have you been smoking?
Sixty years.
You're kidding! How old is the lady?
77, that's what it says on my birth certificate.
I was born in 1900.
Klovis, help him.
Unload the suitcases.
- Can you open the trunk?
- It's open.
Welcome.
- Is this the man?
- Yes.
Welcome!
OFIRO MADHOUSE
I brought beer.
To your arrival.
Holy Mary...
Harold.
Marselas.
Wow...
This party has been going on since seven.
No one has slept for two nights.
Well, dona Sebastijana!
Let's go inside, you need to rest.
- See you.
- Welcome.
Look who's here!
Teresa Victoria.
This is Marselas, he just arrived.
Hello.
- Hi, nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you too.
This is Antonijus, her husband.
They are from Angola.
How are things over there?
Oh, it's a long story.
We can sit down and I'll tell you.
Dona Sebastijana,
they're very noisy today, aren't they?
Don't worry, I'll ask them to lower the music.
My head is splitting.
- I'll take care of that.
- Okay.
- Welcome.
- Thank you, I hope you feel better.
- See you.
- Nice to meet you.
This is Ofiras.
I've been living here for twenty years.
And this is my niece Žeisa's apartment.
I prepared everything for you.
You really prepared everything!
- Everything looks nice and tidy.
- A wonderful apartment.
Completely furnished.
I asked Klovis to clean everything.
Can I put these in the bedroom?
Yes, Klovi.
He cleaned the whole apartment and dusted.
But that wasn't enough for me,
so I brought some incense,
rue leaves, and coarse salt yesterday.
And I performed a cleansing ritual.
You are wonderful.
- Feel at home.
- Thank you very much.
And you? Do you go to school?
- No, I don't go.
- Why?
He arrived here last month from Rio Formoso.
He ran away from his father and uncle.
They wanted to make him the kind of man
they want him to be.
Klovis is a man.
- Right, Klovi?
- Yes, I am a man.
Just not the kind they want.
That's why he helps me here.
He does everything I ask: waters the plants,
picks mangoes, does everything.
And after the soap opera
he goes to sleep.
We'll see about school later.
You have to go to school.
So, there's a cat at home.
Dona Sebastijana, what's this?
Are you allergic to cats?
No, I like cats, but...
They were born in the village.
They were going to be put to sleep, Žeisa brought them here.
Here are Liza and Eliza.
- Liza and Eliza? - Yes.
Liza and Eliza...
Do they live in the apartment?
Sort of.
When Žeisa left, she left the cats with me.
They lived upstairs with me,
but they always came down and scratched the door.
Then I thought, "God,
they miss Žeisa so much that they'll break the door."
So I asked Klovis to cut this hole,
it's terrible.
I said it would look ugly.
Yes, you did.
It's my fault, dear.
But it looks ugly, you can't deny that.
They ruined the door.
Now the cats and dogs walk back and forth.
Girls, this is Marselas, I was talking about.
Marselas, this is Joana.
And that rounder one is Marija.
Hello.
Sorry.
They work in the building.
Good afternoon, dona Sebastijana.
My new neighbor Klaudija
and her daughter Debora.
- Hello.
- Hello, nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you.
What's with the girl's head?
Lice.
They covered her completely.
Klaudija is a teacher and a dentist.
Divorced!
She's wonderful.
- She came to see you.
- Stop it.
Of course not.
Everything will be alright.
I just stopped by.
I have a hard time keeping my tongue behind my teeth.
- Oh dear, dona Sebastijana, please...
- No matter what happens...
No need, dona Sebastijana.
- Nice to meet you.
- Likewise.
- Welcome to our home.
- Thank you.
If you need anything, I live upstairs.
- The floor above?
- Yes.
- Is Klovis there?
I'll ask him to buy cigarettes.
It was nice to meet you.
Now you've seen everything.
I have something for you.
Here you go.
You have to be there very early on Friday morning.
- At five in the morning.
- Thank you.
I'm glad I can help.
I found a house by the sea.
There are coconut palms and a hammock;
we can hang it.
And then, my dear,
I will feel love in your embrace.
In the wonderful radiance.
And then...
We will walk the road no longer just the two of us.
NASRAI
So many sharks.
Yes, grandpa.
I’m drawing the movie poster.
When will I be able to see it?
Fernanda, it can be watched from age 14.
Besides, you'll have nightmares.
I'm already having nightmares, grandpa.
I won't have peace, will I?
Dona Lenira, I'm going to visit my son.
Do you really think you should be here?
I want to see Fernanda, Mr. Aleksandras.
Is he there?
Fernanda.
There was a leg inside the shark.
Were you scared? A human leg?
Yes, a human leg.
- Did you see it on TV?
- On grandpa's radio.
You can't see anything on grandpa's radio.
You can only hear it.
We need to find...
that man who lost his leg and attach it again.
With a screw or...
a little glue, or a string.
- Or sew it.
- Yes.
With that thing.
Dad, can mom be here with us now?
Now mom's memory is with us.
When we think of someone,
that person seems to be with us.
But can she come back?
No, son.
Mom got sick and died.
She won't return.
Do you remember when you caught a cold and had a high fever?
Yes, I remember.
When there is pneumonia,
the temperature rises much higher.
Wow! Up to 50 degrees?
Up to 50.
It's very sad, isn't it?
Yes, but you and I are here.
Mom is also with us – in our memory.
I don't live with you now just because
I can't.
But that's why I came here.
Okay?
So we can live and be together forever.
You and I.
STATE OF SAN PAULO
This "in the city" plays all the time.
Really?
What about the women?
Good.
SÉRGIO MOTTA DAM
There's Oliveira.
- Oliveira!
- Lieutenant.
You know, I usually don’t ask, but...
I got curious.
Who's that old lady at the end?
What's it to me if I tell you?
Snitch.
Damn.
Go to hell.
What's that woman to you?
I'm curious.
Like an itch you can't scratch, right?
Inheritance and envy.
They just arrived.
I'm almost done.
That's the person.
Looks like he fled to Recife.
I’ll find out more and report back.
Is he white, indigenous,
mulatto, or black?
He's white.
What does he do?
It's written in the document.
That one on the right,
with the beard.
A man like him...
As you can understand,
costs more.
I’ll take 60,000 cruzados.
Plus travel, accommodation, and other expenses.
I’ll pay 40,000.
I want first-class services.
And I don’t want any problems.
Don’t contact me anymore.
Pretend I'm not here.
Handle it yourselves.
With all due respect, Mr. Giroči...
Giroti!
Mr. Giroči.
We’ve already won several battles together.
There’s no point in pretending we’re negotiating,
When you know that my price is fair.
60,000 cruzados.
30,000 now.
30,000 later.
– Are you two always together?
– Always.
Yes.
We will sign the contract together.
If you don't agree,
I will understand and respect it.
These holidays passed in an instant.
He is a scoundrel.
I want...
a hole.
A hole?
In his mouth.
Make him mute, do you understand?
You can be calm.
Okay.
Let it be 60,000.
Is there no cavity?
I have dental calculus.
Here. I found one.
And it's huge.
Be careful.
Marcel!
Yes, Dona Sebastiana?
They brought the products. Come meet Valdemar.
- Your time is up. - Oh no, not yet!
I don't want to kiss.
What do you mean?
We've already kissed too much.
Then that's okay.
Do you know the story of Zeus?
Dona Sebastiana's niece?
The owner of these beds,
of this house.
I was told that she left all her belongings behind.
That’s not true.
She was killed by her fiancé.
Angry that she got a scholarship to study in Germany.
What are you saying?
– A great tragedy. – Yes.
How do you know that?
Dona Sebastijana told me.
I noticed that she tells others a different version.
Dona Sebastijana.
– Hello. – How are you doing?
Good, there have been worse times.
But at 77, I'm doing great.
Joana.
Good morning.
Are you ready, dear?
You called, madam?
Can you take my groceries?
Where were you?
I helped a man who had a toothache.
Is he causing you problems?
I'm causing him problems. He's in good hands.
I've fallen in love with this woman.
- Our guardian.
- Yes.
He is well taken care of.
So, tell me, do you bring him every week?
Every Thursday.
My parents have a farm.
We gather what is left,
and I bring fruits, vegetables...
- So we don't have to go there?
- Yes.
Maria!
- Dona Sebastijana.
- Hello.
- Good morning, Valdemar.
- Good morning.
Hello, Marselai.
Just checking our products, the refugees'?
Do you have mangabas today?
No, there are no mangabas left.
Maybe let's avoid that word, okay?
We don't use it here.
"Mangaba"?
"Refugee".
And what are we then?
Flavija.
Wait.
- Can you repeat?
- Which date are you referring to?
February 25, 1977.
And you?
The tape from 1978.
Sebastijanos.
Alright.
The agreement was as follows:
he was supposed to come to the office at 5 a.m.
and invite Anisijus,
who was our contact.
He did just that.
PART 2
IDENTIFICATION DOCUMENTS SERVICE
Budinkis.
Stay alert.
"A man's foot found in a shark..."
There is nothing here and there will never be anything
that I don't already know.
Look.
"Agronomy student still missing."
Lord, what a disaster...
We couldn't have known,
that he was a good guy.
How were we supposed to know?
ROBERTO SANTELMO
IDENTIFICATION DOCUMENTS SERVICE
Look.
Why are you so worried about
what the newspapers are saying?
Because there might be some petty communists
trying to fool us, son.
As long as there is no body, everything will be fine.
One foot won't lead them anywhere.
Oh, what now...
with that foot?
It's in the city morgue.
Marselas?
Yes. Anisijus?
You are punctual.
I was told to come early.
We were all told to do the same.
Let's go inside.
– Das Doresa?
– Yes?
– Please, bring coffee and water.
– Okay.
– No need for a lot of sugar.
– Of course.
– You don't have a São Paulo accent.
– I’m from Pernambuco.
Ah, I see.
But your Pernambucan accent
is kind of strange.
Gerald, at this table, please.
Good morning, Dona Dagmara.
Let’s act like it’s a regular workday, okay?
Sit at that table.
– Where should I sit?
– At the back.
There, at the last table.
Today we are here to
assist Police Chief Euclid,
whom you saw downstairs.
The facility opens to visitors at seven.
Then you will start working.
We arrived at five, but it only opens at seven?
Yes. You’ll have time to settle in.
And most importantly –
we have a quorum.
A quorum for what?
Mrs. Formiga.
No, Elisandra.
I’m waiting for a delivery of clothes this morning.
Could you keep an eye on it?
And tell the boy.
Thank you.
Would you like some [chicken pie]?
Of course.
It looks delicious.
I put three on your account.
– A pie, newbie?
– No, thank you.
Just a cruise with a half.
Thank you, I already had breakfast.
Really?
You can use this room.
– I reserved it for you.
– Thank you.
Hey, everyone.
You have been invited.
Stay here, okay?
Who is that woman?
A girl of about three years old was hit by a car.
and died near her home.
She was the daughter of a housekeeper.
That's why the police chief Euclid...
asked Anisius to gather all of us
before the start of work.
We arrived early for that woman's testimony.
Is this the police station?
No.
But today this is the police station,
to make it more convenient for the wealthy lady.
What a heartless woman.
She sent the maid to buy some bread,
and left the poor girl alone, crying.
The gates were open.
The girl went out – maybe after her mother.
And she was hit by a bus.
It seems that they didn't even tell the girl's mother,
that the location and time of the testimony had been changed.
People,
please return to your tables.
Please.
Let's cooperate with Police Chief Euclid.
People.
Good morning.
Thank you very much for coming.
The questioning will take place in my office.
Please work as if it's just an ordinary workday.
After the testimonies, photojournalists will take pictures.
Please cooperate with Police Chief Euclid.
I am doing what I've been instructed to.
Dear newbie, are you married?
and/or do you enjoy the company of women?
Yes.
But...
I like...
I enjoy.
But it's...
complicated.
CARNIVAL VICTIMS: 91
HUMAN LEG FOUND IN SHARK'S STOMACH
There will be more than 100.
You can be sure of that.
More than 100 dead?
No doubt about it.
- Are you a police officer?
- No.
You look like a police officer.
No, I'm not a police officer.
Euclid Oliveiras Kavalkančis.
- At your service.
- Marselas.
Marselas... what?
Alvešas.
Marselas Alvešas.
The name of a police officer.
No, I'm not a police officer.
A photojournalist is coming now.
That woman is suffering a lot.
Kids are a big trouble.
But anyway, I am the police chief.
My office is next door.
- If you need anything, feel free to ask.
- Thank you very much.
The one who is coming now...
This is Anisijus.
- Have you met him?
- Euklidas.
He starts working with us today.
Highly recommended.
I will show you the archives room.
- Yes.
- Where we keep the archives.
If you need anything, I will gladly help.
Nice to meet you.
That…
Police chief Euklidas
- is quite a character.
Oh, him.
An imperfect man.
Better to keep him close.
On the other hand,
his white son,
Seržas…
God, help us…
Let's go, chief.
It's you again, Deziderijus?
- Good morning.
At this time, chief.
My routine is getting disrupted.
Go to the main doors.
Lord...
A true lover of whores. Damn it.
- This is your workplace.
- Alright.
Jesus Christ!
- Don’t mind the greeting.
- It's all fine.
Your job is constant movement.
This is where identity cards are renewed.
I worked here from 1966
to 1973.
Too many dead.
Say the name.
Maria Aparecida dos Santos.
You're not tricking me, are you?
Your mother?
It’s easier with the father's name.
Alright, then try...
Lorinaldo Fernandes de Melo Solimojesas.
"Solimojesas"...
Now that’s a name!
Everything else is just an addition.
Lorinaldo...
Lorinaldo Fernandes.
Yes, there he is.
- Still a student.
- The father's name is easier.
I’ll be right back.
Marsela,
I'm here to help you.
I work with Elza.
I won’t say anything else.
Do you hear?
- Is that the girl's mother?
- The one who died?
Our orders are to let no one in.
I know she’s in there!
You cannot enter, ma’am.
Dona Kleidi!
Don’t touch me!
Dona Kleidi, I know you’re in there!
I know you’re in there!
I want to go in. I want to talk to her.
I want her to tell me that to my face!
Let me go!
Dona Kleidi, I know you’re in there!
I want to hear why you did this.
Why did you leave my daughter alone?
You won’t let my client enter a public building!
Get away!
Look, who’s by the phone booth.
What’s new, buddy?
Let’s cross the street.
I have something to show you, you’ll like it.
- Now?
- Yes.
I will introduce you to a great guy.
I take my husbands there too, you can come along.
- Chief Euclid, right?
- At your service. Let’s go.
- Across the street?
- It won’t take long.
I need to make a call.
Is it necessary now?
He’s there now.
Your father likes you. You’re lucky.
Let’s go.
Across the street?
Across the street.
Once upon a time there was a king,
who had a big flea,
whom he loved very much
like his son...
[in Portuguese] 38.
He sent for his tailor.
The tailor came...
Here!
Hans!
My friend!
I recognize that voice.
Hello, old buddy. Where’s Hansas?
I brought a friend to meet him.
Tell him I’m not here.
How are you, Chief Euclid?
Couldn’t we do this another time?
- Can I come in? Hans!
- Sir...
Chief Euclid is here!
Hans!
Good morning!
My German friend!
I want to introduce you to my friend.
Marsela, this is Hans.
A real German soldier
from World War II.
This man has stories to tell!
Not today.
Tired.
Show the scars
to my children and friend.
Chief Euclid...
We appreciate your work in the district.
But please come back another time.
Hans is not feeling well today.
Chief, please.
Let me just exchange a few words with Hans.
I just want to see his scars.
Not today,
tired.
Tired!
Hans, you don’t have to do that.
Damn! The black guy speaks German!
Dad, I think he's not in the mood.
Hans,
listen.
Show us the bullet holes
in your legs.
Well, show it.
I think,
he doesn't want to talk.
Show the scars.
Are there sharks in Germany?
Gunshot wounds?
– Impressive!
– Damn it.
– Really disgusting.
– Didn’t I say?
Germany?
Belgium.
That's enough, do you want more?
Hans...
I'm doing this for us.
This idiot
ensures your and our safety.
He will never understand,
that you are Jewish.
Never.
Get out!
Get out of my office!
And take your friends with you.
Get out!
You can only speak like that because
you are a soldier from World War II.
Now get out!
Damn!
BRAZIL – FEDERAL DISTRICT
“Costa and Carpinheiro” partners, how can I help?
I would like to speak to João Pedro.
I’ll connect you right away.
Mr. João, our friend.
Connecting now.
Hello, João. What's going on?
Listen carefully. I hope you are okay.
Don’t say where you are.
– Why?
– This call is not secure.
Our phones are being monitored.
Listen, we can only talk on a secure line.
– Hang up now.
– João…
I will hang up...
Send me the number, and I will call you.
How do I send the number?
Damn it!
Telegram.
PHONE NUMBER 216180.
INTERNAL 22.
I’LL BE WAITING FOR CONTACT AT 5:30 PM. THE END.
– Hello.
Telegram.
Why did you open it?
But I didn’t read it.
If you didn’t read it, why did you open it?
I don’t know what to say…
“The great dragon has been cast out.
It is the great serpent…”
– Pedras?
– It's me.
I would like to speak to Mr. Alexander.
He’s waiting for you.
NO ENTRY
Well, and the stairs…
There’s a woman in the lobby…
possessed by a spirit.
This is that movie.
– Did I receive calls?
– No.
But someone left a message.
Dad, have a good day. Fernanda.
Thank you.
Let’s go.
EMPLOYEES ONLY
Are you showing "Nastrus" again?
Pedras scheduled it for Saturday morning.
Because of that shark’s leg in the stomach.
People like it.
By the way,
Fernanda really wants to see "Nastrus".
I was thinking of bringing him on Saturday.
Are you joking?
I would let him.
It’s too strong for him.
The kid is already having nightmares from the poster.
There…
It happens every day.
Every day.
Fatima loved that window very much.
She liked to sit right where you are sitting now.
I want to ask you.
Looking into your eyes.
When you were married to her,
did you often cheat on her?
What are you talking about after so long?
You cheated, didn’t you?
Mr. Alexander…
Fatima and I loved each other very much.
You know better than anyone else, right?
I know.
Fernanda is the biggest proof of that.
So,
you cheated, didn’t you?
Wait.
Someone is calling you.
Hello, Joan. It worked.
It's nice to hear you and know that you are okay.
I have to speak quickly, I don't have many tokens.
He managed to put your name on the Federal Police list.
This means you cannot leave the country.
That's very strange.
I can't travel?
I'm trying to comprehend this.
He is manipulating.
This is a high-level dirty game.
I’m telling you,
he removed a serious prosecutor from the case –
favorable to the regime, but serious –
and replaced him with a fraudster,
…his friend.
Damn!
I have to say,
the situation is very bad.
So please,
don’t stick your head in,
stay in the shadows.
This is my last token.
Listen carefully.
Elza
is now the most important figure in this story.
Elza.
A great place.
A technician from Rio stays here.
This way he saves on hotel costs.
– Mr. Alexander?
– Alexander de Jesus do Nascimento.
– I’m Elza.
– Nice to meet you.
– I’m Valdemar.
– Hello.
How should I address you?
You can call me by my name here – Armando.
It’s a great honor to speak with you here.
Didn’t you say you were using a fake name?
Isn’t that bad?
Yes, not very good.
And thank you for the free tickets.
We just watched a movie.
Did you like it?
I’m not a religious person, but it was scary.
Valdemar almost wet his pants.
I don’t like horror movies.
Can I record our conversation?
Record whatever you want.
Recording.
It’s similar to
American witness protection programs.
There, everything is done with big resources
and government funds.
And here everything is somewhat improvised, Brazilian style.
And aimed at protecting you from Brazil.
How many people do you protect?
With you – four people in Recife.
Two more in Fortaleza and one in Salvador.
Are we all in the same house in Recife?
Look, each case is different.
– So, we all help each other.
– Yes.
And who pays for all this?
It is paid for by the daughter…
from a very wealthy family in São Paulo…
that has been tearing the country apart for a long time.
How did work go today?
So, you hired me at the police station –
are you serious?
No, it’s not a police station.
You applied to the Identification Documents Department.
Yes.
I will try to find
the only document proving,
that my deceased mother actually existed.
But today that place was a police station.
With the police chief and everything.
Did you two talk?
He’s a real jerk,
a son of a bitch.
The worst part is,
it seemed like he liked me.
Just know – we have an ally there.
Anisius.
Is it safe for him to know who I am?
Anisius helps.
But he doesn’t know who you are and what we are doing with you.
Tell me about the passports.
Mine and my son’s.
I don’t know if you know,
but I’m on the Federal Police list,
which prohibits me from traveling.
Given the situation,
we agree that you need a fake passport.
We can take care of that.
I can get the documents,
but it will take a few days.
What’s happening here?
I don’t understand.
Why do I need a fake passport?
I haven’t done anything wrong…
And what’s in it for you?
Who are you?
I’m a pediatrician.
Just trying to help.
Armando, let’s not talk about that now.
Think about your son.
My grandson.
Think about my daughter, Fatima.
Mr. Aleksandras, I constantly think about my son.
I’m very sorry about your daughter, Mr. Aleksandras.
And your wife, Armando.
How could this country lose
such a woman as Fatima?
Brazil will pay dearly for this.
I don't agree.
With all due respect.
She will not pay anything.
She won't pay a damn thing.
Armando, I admire you,
but you should leave.
If I were you,
I would get out of here as soon as possible.
I would accept their help and leave today.
That's why I organized it.
Mr. Aleksandras…
We need to protect what we still have.
You and my grandson.
I will be in the projector room.
Lock the doors.
We would like to know more
about Enrique Castro Giroči
and how he got involved in this.
I will tell you everything.
I will get all of this
off my chest.
This is a conversation.
Being recorded.
Tell me about that…
Enrique Giroči.
I...
I am not a violent person.
But this man…
I would kill him even with a hammer.
I would crush his skull with a hammer.
Are you…
Do you carry a weapon?
No, but I know how to use a hammer.
I need to go to the bathroom.
She paused the recording to go to the bathroom...
We would like to know more
about Enrike Castro Giroči
and how he got involved in this.
Flavia?
...about herself.
It's a conversation.
What dates are you listening to?
- Excuse me?
- What dates are you listening to?
It's Elza with "Marsel," in quotes,
February 25, 1977.
I haven't finished yet.
Marselas is Armandas, do you know that?
That's exactly what I just heard,
and I got confused.
So Marselas is actually Armandas.
- That's a fake name.
- Yes.
You're smart, Flavia!
Which ones are you listening to?
Anisija's tapes.
From '76.
Yes.
I need to go to the restroom.
How did you meet Giročius?
He came for a visit to the university.
As the head of the department,
I would sometimes meet guests at the Recife airport.
He was on the board of the state electric company
"Eletrobras",
which belonged to the Ministry of Mining and Energy.
So, you are Armandas.
I read your CV.
I imagined you differently.
- I'll take that as a compliment.
- Yes. It's hot, isn't it?
What was your first impression?
About Giročius?
Jerk.
And his son - another jerk.
How long have you been the head of the department?
I returned after my postdoctoral studies
about two years ago.
I also made up for the research leave.
And I was elected.
Have you ever considered working in industry?
You could use a good cold industrial shower.
I enjoy doing research.
Did he say "industrial shower"?
Yes, I needed an "industrial shower."
When was that?
That was
in August 1974.
We introduced him to everyone,
in the department.
There was Luanda Azevedo,
Marcellus Vasconcelos, Sebastian Pires...
We showed him the entire building.
We showed him the laboratories, all the projects...
The electric autonomy project,
the electric car project...
The leather processing machine,
which was the pride of our department.
Let me introduce my colleagues.
Hello.
– Hi.
– So, this is Suzy Shafer...
– Nice to meet you.
– From the University of Leeds.
Sendzejus Jeslin
from Quebec Technical University.
Are you British?
No. I’m American. From New York.
– But Sendzejus...
– I’m British.
You’re British?
– Yes.
– Really?
Yes. We studied together in Leeds.
I now live in Quebec.
Of course.
And here we are.
He’s a great guy.
That's how it was. The next day.
There was a meeting.
In that meeting, he practically...
shut us up.
To save time,
I'll get straight to the point.
Speaking of "Eletrobras,"
farthest from Pernambuco,
the work you are doing here,
should be part of the whole, in my opinion.
You are too independent,
separated from us in the South.
I would like to focus on Rio.
some of your research
and the subjects of the decisions.
To avoid old discussions about this,
how the work differs in the North and the South.
I know you speak with a different accent,
you have a different way of working.
Even your department head – a hairy guy.
Right, Armand?
Long live the differences, right?
What I am trying to say is,
I was surprised by what I saw here.
I apologize.
Just because...
for clarity.
All our projects are published in the official publication.
I don’t understand why you’re surprised.
– Let me finish. – Unless you haven't read it.
I meant it positively.
– Just to be clear. – It’s a compliment.
Alright...
By the way, the leather processing technology...
measuring the area of leather,
is important to the local culture.
For bulls, goats, cows...
It's important for the economy of the Northeastern region.
I like it.
It's a regional center, not a national one,
Let alone international.
Let's take a look at the electric car, the project you showed me.
By the way, Armandas is also working on it.
In Canada, they are being conducted
more advanced research.
In fact, we purchased 12 prototypes from the Canadian consortium.
– Through "Eletrobras." I would like to add...
You and your company are part of that consortium.
"Eletrobras."
"Eletrobras" indeed acquired 12 prototypes from the consortium.
"Eletrobras"?
– Not your company? – "Eletrobras." Can I continue?
So...
I am curious,
whether taxpayer money
should be spent on such projects.
In the northeast...
He cannot speak seriously,
when they themselves have to deal with so many problems.
Moreover,
competing with larger ones abroad.
Mr. Giroci,
I am Luanda Azevedo, a research professor,
with a degree from the Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul.
– You are from the South? – Yes.
All our projects are funded.
from public research funds.
And we have partnership projects,
funded by independent foreign foundations.
It's time to review your funding criteria,
especially independence.
Luanda was the first to fall.
She went to work
in the São Paulo metro,
where that jerk was in the Technical Commission.
Did this happen to the whole team?
Yes.
It was a real "industrial shower."
He cut funding for state universities
for personal gain.
It's just...
And then I was
poured over with accusations.
I don't know if you know,
but two fabricated articles were published,
a coordinated attack against you,
In the newspapers of Rio and São Paulo.
Thank God,
I didn’t see anything in the Recife newspapers.
Everything will pass.
I hope it will pass.
Mr. Aleksandras,
please sit here so I can see you.
I didn't tell the story in order.
The evening before that meeting
we went to dinner.
I,
Fatima,
Giročis and his son.
She started as your secretary, right?
To the restroom.
What a beautiful woman you have.
Would you like some water?
Yes, please.
I invited you to dinner with my wife.
And she just said that she is a teacher, right?
But I know why you’re doing this.
It's for the lithium battery research, right?
I patented the research.
It’s my project.
It’s a small breakthrough, but the patent is mine.
Pass the whiskey.
My sense of smell never fails me, does it, son?
You know me.
This guy uses the university to patent research.
– I demand respect.  – Don’t tell me...
He uses the public system to reach the market.
We need to shut down all these shitty institutions.
– Easy money, right?  – I demand respect.
Public money is easy money.
I am the head of the research center you attend.
I am an employee of the university that accepts you.
– I can't believe it.  – I knew I had to come here.
I knew.
Armand, my field is engineering.
I run the family business,
created through sweat and hard work.
My father is Italian, from Genoa.
My blood is Italian.
You have no idea what you're getting into, kid.
You are a communist.
– I'm not a communist.  – You are.
Are you a capitalist?
– More of a communist than a capitalist.  – Listen.
You know the map.
Brazil.
North.
Everyone has their own place.
Good job, man.
Fatima.
I work at the university that accepts you.
I'm not a little kid, as you just called me.
I demand respect.  Dinner is paid for.
Meeting tomorrow at 8:30.  The car will be there at 8.
If you want to go, go; if not, don’t go.
That idiot can stay behind.
Just let me say something quickly.
I got up because I felt the need to urinate and vomit.
As soon as I got up – it passed.
Control your woman.
You treated us disrespectfully.
Very disrespectfully.
– Let's go.  – Wait.
– No, no...  – Control your woman.
Now you'll listen.
I was silent all evening out of respect for Armand.
Very disrespectful, especially towards a father in front of his son.
Now I am thinking about my father, who is a humble man.
He started working at the age of nine.
This is a man.
This is a man. Do you hear me?
Like my husband. This is a man.
Let's go.
But you, you are drunk too.
You should be ashamed. What kind of people are you?
Oh, the secretary is that bitch who gave birth to you. Go fuck yourself.
– Calm down!
– Go to hell.
Go to hell yourself.
– Sit down.
– Armand...
Armand, don't get into this...
– Everyone has their place.
– Calm down.
I haven't hit anyone since school days.
In the gym in 1950.
And the meeting still happened...
As I said.
Did Fatima really say that about me?
Yes, Mr. Aleksandras.
Alright.
Well then...
Giročius is a criminal.
His place is in prison.
And when I say that,
I don't mean a farm colony.
He should be in Carandiru.
What he is doing is treason.
He is a con artist...
and a murderer.
In your, let's say, "refugee" group,
What I want to make clear the most is your case.
I understand...
Those two foreign universities want me.
They are probably pressuring you.
Not because of that...
Those foreign universities
really want you, that's great.
But let's not talk about that.
We have been informed that two men were hired.
to find you in Recife.
That's not good.
They are from the state of Rio, working together.
The senior one is Augustas Borba.
A former soldier, discharged from the army in 1970.
He was based in Minas Gerais.
He wasn't even needed by the lousy armed forces.
He is a scum.
The younger one, Bobis, is his stepson.
They say that the stepfather killed Bobi's mother.
And now they are working together.
They say that hired killers are looking for me?
Yes.
Is Giročis behind that?
And what do you say?
A week, at most ten days.
In your hands in four days.
Four days?
Such disrespect.
Fatima, for you.
And to your son, who is with me.
She was so healthy...
Four days?
PERNAMBUCO FORENSIC MEDICAL SERVICE
I need to talk to you about something outside.
About what?
It’s very important.
– Why?
– It’s better if we go outside.
Keep her outside.
Let’s go, Lucius.
We're moving.
Lindinho is probably turning over in his grave.
Damn!
There will be a bomb here!
Listen.
"The hairy leg strikes again!"
The cartoon turned out great.
Hairy leg!
Piranhas will come out tonight.
You will throw this crap away, Sergei.
- What?
- You will throw it away.
Here.
Stop here.
It's good here, alright!
I will call.
San Luis movie theater, good evening?
I would like to speak with Mr. Alexander.
I think he has already left.
I will connect you with the booth.
Thank you.
Incoming call.
Could I speak with Mr. Alexander?
He left early today.
Can you tell me who is calling?
I just want to confirm, his name is
Alexander de Chesus do Nasimiento, right?
I can't help you with that, man.
Leave your name,
and I will pass it on to him...
What is this...
It seems his father-in-law works at the San Luis movie theater,
Not elsewhere.
Now there's a man!
They are here.
Damn it.
Look at this tourist!
My colonel is punctual.
Look at that hat!
For your sacred honor!
– Police truck?
– Get in.
– Let's go.
– That's what I'm talking about.
Everyone inside!
This is my colonel.
"My colonel." Look who's talking.
My lieutenant.
The lieutenant is my ass.
First lieutenant!
And I am proud of the uniform I once wore.
Allow me to introduce my stepson – Bobby.
Or Abdias.
On the birth certificate – Abdias.
He's a big guy.
Is everything okay, Abdias?
Does he shoot well?
You can't even imagine.
This is Seržas.
Mother's son.
The next one is Arlindas,
He's like a son.
I prefer "Bobis" more, Mr. Euclid.
Leader Euclid, I don't sell sweets on the street,
Okay?
I didn't spend my whole life for this,
to be called some "Mr." now.
What even is "Bobis"? Is that a man's name?
Did we run out of masculine names that day?
Leader Euclid.
– That's better.
– He's tough, kid.
He doesn't like being called "Mr.," it makes him angry.
Got it, right? So calm down now.
Are you here on a mission?
Well, let's not go there.
Never mix friendship with work, okay?
The carnival was a real show.
Almost 100 missing.
I read about this extravaganza in the newspapers.
Did a shark even swallow a foot?
A story for tourists.
Speaking of which,
shall we go for a "ride"?
"Ride"?
We'll go for a "ride."
Damn, yes. We're definitely going for a "ride."
Where are we going?
Calm down, kiddo.
Today we are just tourists,
we’re not going for a "ride."
What's the plan?
Everything is arranged.
One is "157."
The other is "157" and "213."
They are at the back.
Already there?
"157" and "213."
Damn it.
"213" means...?
Most often rape.
"157" – "armed robbery with murder."
Just good guys.
"Local resident, Pedro Jorge do Nascimento,
27 years old, student,
living in the Mustardinja district,
went for a walk in the evening in May 13th Park.
with a friend, Alexandrino Borges, 32 years old.
a dental prosthetist, living in the Bomba do Emeterio district,
when they were unexpectedly
a shadow pounced on them, emerging from nowhere.
and began to kick them.
It's so strange.
Strange, but we all know what this is, don’t we?
But the newspaper writes about it as if it were news!
Teresa, read about that attack. Amazing.
Read it.
– But you've already read it.
– I have.
But it sounds much better with your English accent.
Thank you.
Oh my dear!
Hello everyone.
– Hello.
– Oh, my dear.
– Is everything okay?
– Yes.
Marcel, I'm glad you came to say goodbye.
Dona Sebastijana told me.
– I wanted to be with you. – Hello!
I’m Gerald, Sebastiana's friend.
"Hairy Leg" is very popular in Casa Amarelo.
A bit anarchic, isn't it?
– Can I call?
– If not long-distance.
Help me with the dishes, Klovi.
I don't like Recife.
They didn't treat me well here.
I'm sorry for calling so late.
I would like to leave a message for Mr. Alexander.
I really want to talk to my son.
It's a strange city, but...
That's fine.
The "Hairy Leg" that jumps,
would be a hit in Luanda!
Thank you, Suleika.
Thank you.
– Is this sugarcane vodka?
– Yes.
Long live Mr. Marselas.
Marselas is your fictional name, right?
Marselas...
My name is Armand.
But call me Marselas if you want.
I would rather not reveal my...
real name.
"Teresa Victoria"...
that was the name of my dear aunt.
I actually always wanted to be "Teresa Victoria".
A beautiful name.
I like compound names.
Names are used for your safety.
It's not easy when you're called by a foreign name.
It's just a precaution.
My name is Sebastiana.
I haven't changed it.
My name is Clovis.
Just Clovis, actually.
I wish I were as brave as you,
I really do.
But it's not easy to live in the face of a deadly threat.
I am in the presence of a deadly threat.
I am also in the presence of a deadly threat.
Let's lighten up,
I will play some music.
Dona Sebastijana, I didn't mean to ruin the mood.
Help me.
I said that because...
I am alive, strong.
I have a son.
I want to live.
Just...
I found out today,
that death is imminent.
It was quite a surprise.
For someone who conflicted with both sides in Angola,
finding refuge here
was very good.
Now Antonio and I are leaving.
On a plane without the Portuguese flag, we insisted on that.
Teresa, you talk too much.
Dona Sebastijana,
you are the best.
Thank you very much.
You're welcome.
Where are you going, Teresa?
There’s no need to talk about it.
But thank you.
My niece Žeisa loved this song.
To be more precise, she loves it.
I think this is for me.
Hello, Mr. Aleksandrai.
Good.
We'll talk later, have a good evening.
I don't want to see you sad. Come and see my little museum.
Look here...
This is my niece,
Žeisa, when she was little.
Here she is already grown up.
And here are you?
That's me with my boyfriend back then, Andrea.
It was in Italy, in Sassuolo.
Really? You lived in Italy?
For seven years. From 1936 to 1942.
- You never told me that. - You never asked.
I returned only after the war ended.
I went to Italy to study music.
And I stayed when everything started to go downhill.
I couldn't go back.
I was a communist there. Then an anarchist.
Or the other way around, I don't remember.
I saw with my own eyes things,
that I won't tell you about.
I’ll take them to the grave.
I also did three things there,
that I won't tell you about.
But I did them and I had to do them.
To finish up –
a toast to all of you!
A toast.
- To my friend Žeraldas. - Thank you.
Life has its bad things, but there are also good ones.
To Harold, who is not Harold.
To Marcel,
who is Armands.
To this woman, who is Teresa Victoria to me.
She is going to Sweden with Antonijus.
A toast to Claudia,
who is Claudia.
And to Deborah,
who, I’m sure, will live in a better Brazil.
She will grow up in a better Brazil, with less evil.
To everyone’s health.
To health.
Thank you, Dona Sebastijana.
Calmly.
Look at me, I am here.
PART 3. BLOOD TRANSFUSION
Damn it!
Vilmarai.
Mr. Bobis.
Mr. Augustas.
Is this the man?
This is the man.
I inquired, they say you are the man.
I don’t know.
Is he capable of doing the job?
Yes, he is capable.
The job is here, in Recife.
It requires a lot of responsibility and reliability.
Poor or rich?
Hell knows!
Looks lavish, but is not rich.
Looks luxurious and is rich.
It will be more expensive.
Does he have a gun?
No.
He is a coward.
I will do it for 4,000.
Damn it!
What do you use for the job?
Medium length: 38.
Accuracy guaranteed.
I’ll give 2,000.
The price is 4,000. I’ll do it for 4,000.
You work this shoddy job,
carrying sugar like an animal, for cents.
It's an easy job.
We have information that will help you.
“Like an animal”...
I don’t like how you speak.
This is our man.
4,000.
4,000 agreed.
But you’re going now.
2,000 in advance.
Right now.
Severinai. I need to leave.
- For half an hour. - Okay.
- You are responsible. - Of course.
if Santa Cruz Wins Today,
I’ll buy beer.
I’ll be back soon.
Okay, Aleksandrai.
- SORRY. - Hello.
- Is Mr. Aleksandras here? - he just left.
Really?
Too Bad.
Hairy foot stole that Leg from the morgue
Marija Aparesida dos Santos
Mary Augusta?
- Mary aparesida? - Mary aparesida.
There aren't that many of them.
Is sher mother?
You are determined, aren’t you?
My mother passed away; I would like to have her documents.
Even if just one.
And I know her identity card was issued here.
I am determined to find the file.
I hope you do.
Good morning.
- Good morning, boss. - Good morning.
Are identity cards issued here?
Yes, sir.
Brenda Oliveira da Mata.
I just need to talk to someone.
Maria Eugenija...
Armando.
His name is Marselas.
Elisandžela, you can let him in.
- Is everything okay? - I called you Armando.
- How about Fernandas? - Good.
He asked me to pass this to you.
I had to swear,
that I would come in the morning.
Turn it over.
"Dad,
Grandpa and Grandma are very nice,
but I want to live with you.
I think I'm starting
to forget Mom.
Come back soon,
Fernandas."
You take my grandson.
I'm taking my son.
And you should take him.
You should take him.
I need to go.
Did you find your mother's document?
Klaudija Andrade Lima Melo.
I'm sorry...
Mariana da Roša Pineiro.
Mariana?
Thank you.
Next, Kaua Baros Campos.
Demostenis Gera Fereira.
- I'm sorry. - Yes?
Is he Armando?
No.
His name is Marselas.
Armando.
Armando!
His name is not Armando.
Take a few guys, intimidate him.
We only have two patrol cars.
I'm sorry.
Commander Euclides, I'm sorry.
Yes, Marselas.
I need to talk to you.
Please.
You know I don't carry a weapon.
We are under-protected down there.
A man like that
appeared, harassing girls.
What the hell.
He threatened me...
He’s causing problems, that’s why I came to you.
You need a weapon, buddy.
Makes you respected.
Stretch out your hand.
Stretch...
Your hand, he wants to see your hand.
Stretch it out.
That's right.
You're getting nervous.
Have you met his wife?
No, I don’t know him.
He’s down there now.
Commander Euclides...
I wouldn’t have come here
to ask for your help,
if I didn't think it was a dangerous situation.
- Arlindai? - Yes?
Go check.
Right away, I’m eager.
- Let’s go. - Thank you, commander.
Let’s go together, something is happening.
- Do we really have to go now? - It’s quick here.
Scammers and con artists
Lieutenant.
Hey, lieutenant.
You have a call.
Mr. Augustas, this is Vilmaras.
I found a man.
Where?
In the office where they issue identity cards.
Is it really him?
Definitely.
I looked closely.
Shall we go all the way?
Is Bobis with you?
No, he stayed at the cinema.
That's better.
Get rid of him.
I'll get rid of him.
Right in the nose.
He's in the phone booth.
That guy with the red hat?
Let's go, Markas.
I have your remaining money.
Hey, man...
Are you bothering our friend?
Show us your passport.
You know, I know this guy.
I forgot my passport today.
Shots fired!
There's a shootout over there. It's a real hell.
Damn.
Don't do tomorrow
what you can do the day after tomorrow!
Long live procrastination!
Long live collective inaction!
The man with the red hat?
That way?
Free love costs more!
Social insurance
the so-called foresight!
Desires just keep growing!
Neither the future nor glory means anything!
What I see – it's just the wind!
Look at the books, look – the books!
Help us...
Where is Arlindas?
– Did you see what happened?
– Yes.
Yet another true love.
Love is rebellious.
It doesn't grow in a cage.
She needs freedom.
She doesn't beg for alms.
Seek your own and live it,
while it’s still here
and never returned.
I am a plant, I have roots,
I am a beast of the forest,
walking free and happy,
following my destiny,
earning money – there will be more tomorrow.
My path must be free,
He doesn’t beg for alms.
So take care of your love while it’s still here.
These cases cannot be taken out of the room.
All lines are occupied due to what happened.
Tell me, your name is not Marsel, right?
"Like an animal"...
Elza.
I need the passports now.
Elza...
My time in Recife is over.
Step back! Scatter!
CARNIVAL COUNT: 91 DEATHS
SOUTHERN TOURIST SHOT BY A BARBER
The motive could have been revenge.
Dani.
Yes, Flavia?
Speak.
Have you tried to find out what happened to these people?
You know that I'm a bit worried?
I tried searching online, but there's nothing.
They all lived before the Google era.
We need to review the newspapers.
Yes, but there will be more work.
I'm listening to Anisijus, who tried to help Armand, you know?
You've gone back to Armand's case?
It shook you a bit, didn’t it?
Yes, I needed a break from that.
Well...
I don't know why, but this guy's story touched me.
Probably because my family is from Pernambuco.
My grandfather, who was practically my father.
I liked listening to Armand's voice in the headphones.
He had a nice voice.
THE MURDERED SCIENTIST WAS ACCUSED OF CORRUPTION.
Take him?
Armandas Solimojesas, 43, shot...
The crime is considered contracted.
Say "daddy."
Thank you, goodbye.
– Good evening.
I would like to meet with Dr. Fernando de Melo Solimojes.
He is waiting for me.
Dr. Fernando.
– Flavia, right?
– Exactly.
Are you a donor?
Yes.
How much do you weigh?
52 kilograms.
Flavia?
Dr. Fernando.
Very nice to meet you.
How are you?
I was joking when I said I would only meet if you donate blood.
Still, it's for the good.
It's my first time donating blood.
You are in good hands.
Right, Roza?
Everything is fine.
Can I see my blood?
From Minas Gerais?
Yes, but I lived in São Paulo for a few years.
At first, I didn't want to,
but I'm glad I did.
- Can I take this?
- Yes, please.
Thank you, Roza.
Now for a snack, I’ll get her some chocolate milk.
I know your father spent some time
looking for your mother’s identity document
here in Recife, right?
It's recorded on tapes.
You see, I don't know...
I didn't know that.
About my paternal grandmother,
I only know her name,
"Maria Aparesida dos Santos,"
also known as "the Indian."
That's all I know.
Do you have any documents about your grandmother?
Nothing. I have never seen her.
No photos, nothing.
No records at all.
From my paternal grandfather
she got pregnant
by a maid's daughter from Bonito,
here in Pernambuco.
My grandfather was 17,
and my grandmother was 14, still a child.
She was like...
She did all the housework.
She was like a maid...
Like...
enslaved... or captured.
I don't know...
She was definitely enslaved.
And my grandmother was known as...
Everyone called her "the Indian," just "the Indian."
And my father, her son...
Everyone said he was a "handsome" boy.
So she was "the Indian,"
and my father was "handsome."
You see?
It's not simple.
It's very hard for me to talk about this...
I do it because you insisted.
You are really not just anyone,
you sent emails, you called...
But it's hard for me to talk about it.
But...
And your father Armand?
My father Armand
was born from that relationship
between a 17-year-old boy and a 14-year-old girl.
And...
The wealthy side of the family...
"wealthy," so to speak...
That is my grandfather's family.
They took my father to raise him,
while his mother could do nothing,
she was a child.
Listen, Fernanda, here’s what happened:
I work at a private university,
which paid me to transcribe the tapes
from the archive.
And now they want to recover the tapes,
in my opinion because
they contain sensitive information.
So they asked for all the tapes back.
But it doesn’t matter,
because I made copies of all the recordings.
I said you were not just anyone, right?
But that's the reason
I came.
I enjoyed listening to your father's testimony.
Hearing how people talked about him.
Flavia...
How did those recordings reach you?
Through Sara Gebert's daughter,
your father knew her as "Elza,"
when he was being hunted.
Flavia, I don't want to delve into this.
Okay?
Okay.
Actually...
I brought this,
with all the recordings I copied.
Everything I received,
is here.
Your father's voice is here,
and people talking about him.
It's yours.
You can take it and do whatever you want.
You know, my grandfather Alexander...
who raised me
and whom I consider my father...
He told me that...
He always used to tell this story.
When my father...
On the day my father died,
I had just washed up and was ready.
I chose my favorite clothes and stood
by the house, waiting for him.
He planned to come pick me up.
To be honest, I don't remember that.
Sometimes when someone else tells,
you create a memory.
But I don't know if I remember that day.
I talk to you about him, but I...
In fact, I don't remember him.
In fact,
you remember my father more than I do.
I don't think I helped you much.
It's all right.
It was wonderful to meet you.
This trip to Recife is also an opportunity for me
to meet relatives,
whom I only know by phone.
Do you have family here?
My grandfather is from here.
He worked for the family
not far from here, at the Crying Boy Square.
I like the name "Crying Boy."
It's a great name for a square.
I've heard about that place since I was a child.
I just happened to end up here.
Do you want to hear about the coincidence?
When I was little,
I really wanted to see the movie "Nasrai."
– I know.
– You know?
My grandfather wouldn’t let me,
just the poster scared me –
a hand with big jaws.
He was a movie projector operator at the San Luis cinema.
One day, he took me to see it.
Unexpectedly.
I got ready and went.
Since the day I saw the movie,
nightmares about the shark disappeared.
There's the coincidence.
Guess where I saw the movie.
I don't know any local cinemas.
Right here.
There used to be a cinema here?
The Boa Vista cinema, where I watched "Jaws."
– It's changed a lot.
– It's changed.
It's a completely different place.
And I work here now.
– Your car?
– It's already here.
Thank you, Fernanda.
Thank you.
SECRET AGENT
The production and distribution of this film were
financed from public and private funds,
creating more than 1300
direct and indirect jobs.
Moreover, culture is not only part of a country's identity –
it is also an industry.